<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: music | sdd]]></title>
  <link href="http://cqror.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cqror.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-21T13:33:10+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://cqror.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[qichunren]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[听《Sara》]]></title>
    <link href="http://cqror.com/blog/2011-05-03-listen-to-sara/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-03T17:10:12+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://cqror.com/blog/listen-to-sara</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sara这首歌太好听了，虽然没有清楚具体是唱什么，但我感觉是讲一个故事，很好奇，我找到了歌词。</p>

<p>Sara
塞拉</p>

<p>鲍勃迪伦</p>

<p>I laid on a dune, I looked at the sky,
When the children were babies and played on the beach.
You came up behind me, I saw you go by,
You were always so close and still within reach.</p>

<p>我躺在沙丘上，我向天空凝望，
那时孩子都还小，嬉戏在沙滩上。
我见你走来，又擦身而去
你就是如此接近，近到触手可及。</p>

<p>Sara, Sara,
Whatever made you want to change your mind?
Sara, Sara,
So easy to look at, so hard to define.</p>

<p>塞拉，塞拉，
究竟是什么让你开始改变？
塞拉，塞拉，
一切看似简单，却难以细言。</p>

<p>I can still see them playin' with their pails in the sand,
They run to the water their buckets to fill.
I can still see the shells fallin' out of their hands
As they follow each other back up the hill.</p>

<p>他们在沙堆提桶玩耍的情景依稀可见，
孩子们奔跑着把手中的水桶注满。
我还能看到正从他们手中滑落的贝壳，
排队退往沙丘的他们一个接着一个。</p>

<p>Sara, Sara,
Sweet virgin angel, sweet love of my life,
Sara, Sara,
Radiant jewel, mystical wife.
塞拉，塞拉，
我此生的挚爱，可爱圣洁的天使，
塞拉，塞拉，
光彩照人的宝石，魔力四射的妻子。</p>

<p>Sleepin' in the woods by a fire in the night,
Drinkin' white rum in a Portugal bar,
Them playin' leapfrog and hearin' about Snow White,
You in the marketplace in Savanna-la-Mar.</p>

<p>夜晚躺在篝火旁度过，
在葡萄牙酒馆把白朗姆酒斟酌，
他们玩着“跳背”游戏，聆听白雪公主的故事，
而你却在滨海萨凡纳的集市。</p>

<p>Sara, Sara,
It's all so clear, I could never forget,
Sara, Sara,
Lovin' you is the one thing I'll never regret.</p>

<p>塞拉，塞拉，
回忆如此清晰，我永不忘记，
塞拉，塞拉，
爱你之情我会终生不渝。</p>

<p>I can still hear the sounds of those Methodist bells,
I'd taken the cure and had just gotten through,
Stayin' up for days in the Chelsea Hotel,
Writin' "Sad-Eyed Lady of the Lowlands" for you.</p>

<p>卫理公会圣钟之声我还能听见，
我已挺过难关，一切都已烟消云散，
在切尔西饭店没日没夜的这些天里，
写出了“忧伤眼神的低地女人”给你。</p>

<p>Sara, Sara,
Wherever we travel we're never apart.
Sara, oh Sara,
Beautiful lady, so dear to my heart.</p>

<p>塞拉，塞拉，
无论去哪我们从没分开。
塞拉，噢，塞拉，
美丽的女人，是我心上的爱。</p>

<p>How did I meet you? I don't know.
A messenger sent me in a tropical storm.
You were there in the winter, moonlight on the snow
And on Lily Pond Lane when the weather was warm.</p>

<p>我怎么遇见你？我不知道。
信使来时正逢一场热带风暴。
冬夜的你是白雪上的月光，
天暖时便是月光洒在了百合池旁。</p>

<p>Sara, oh Sara,
Scorpio Sphinx in a calico dress,
Sara, Sara,
You must forgive me my unworthiness.</p>

<p>塞拉，噢，塞拉，
身着印花礼服的迷幻女王，
塞拉，塞拉，
我的卑微请你一定原谅。</p>

<p>Now the beach is deserted except for some kelp
And a piece of an old ship that lies on the shore.
You always responded when I needed your help,
You gimme a map and a key to your door.</p>

<p>如今废弃的沙滩只剩几片水藻，
还有一艘破船在岸边停靠。
当我每每求助，你都会回应，
你会等在心门，给我方向给我指引。</p>

<p>Sara, oh Sara,
Glamorous nymph with an arrow and bow,
Sara, oh Sara,
Don't ever leave me, don't ever go.</p>

<p>塞拉，噢，塞拉，
一身戎装的真命女神，
塞拉，塞拉，
别离开我，永远别走。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
